INSERT INTO artefacts (artefact_name, extension, time_period, geo_position, significance)
VALUES ('Autobiography of Weni', '.png', 'c.2280BCE', 'Abydos', 'Records the earliest known Egyptian military campaigns in Sinai and the Levant.'),
       ('Sebek-khu Stele', '.png', 'c.1860BCE', 'Abydos', 'Records the earliest known Egyptian military campaign in Retjenu, including Sekmem (s-k-m-m, thought to be Shechem)'),
       ('Statue of Idrimi', '.jpg', 'c.1500BCE', 'Alalakh', 'Records the earliest certain cuneiform reference to Canaan'),
       ('Merneptah Stele', '.jpg', 'c.1209BCE', 'Thebes', 'While alternative translations have been put forward, the majority of biblical archeologists translate a set of hieroglyphs on Line 27 as "Israel", such that it represents the first documented instance of the name Israel in the historical record, and the only record in Ancient Egypt.'),
       ('Bubastite Portal', '.jpg', 'c.925BCE', 'Karnak', 'Records the conquests and military campaigns in c.925 BCE of Shoshenq I, of the Twenty-second Dynasty, identified with the biblical Shishaq. Towns identified include Rafah (rph), Megiddo (mkdi) and Ajalon (iywrn)'),
       ('Mesha stele', '.png', 'c.850BCE', 'Dhiban, Jordan', 'Describes the victories of Moabite king Mesha over the House of Omri (kingdom of Israel)'),
       ('Kurkh Monoliths', '.png', 'c.850BCE', 'Üçtepe, Bismil', 'The Shalmaneser III monolith contains a description of the Battle of Qarqar at the end.'),
       ('Black Obelisk of Shalmaneser III', '.png', 'c.825BCE', 'Nimrud', 'Contains what is thought to be the earliest known picture of a biblical figure: possibly Jehu son Omri (mIa-ú-a mar mHu-um-ri-i), or Jehu\'s ambassador, kneeling at the feet of Shalmaneser III.'),
       ('Saba\'a Stele', '.png', 'c.800BCE', 'Saba\'a', 'Records Adad-Nirari III\'s Assyrian campaign to Pa-la-áš-tu (Philistia)'),
       ('Tel Dan Stele', '.png', 'c.800BCE', 'Tel Dan', 'Its significance for the biblical version of Israel\'s past lies particularly in lines 8 and 9, which mention a "king of Israel" and a "house of David". '),
       ('Nimrud Slab', '.png', 'c.800BCE', 'Nimrud', 'Describes Adad-nirari III\'s early Assyrian conquests in Palastu (Phillistia), Tyre, Sidon, Edom and Humri (the latter understood as the Kingdom of Israel (Samaria)).'),
       ('Nimrud Tablet K.3751', '.png', 'c.733BCE', 'Nimrud', 'Describes Tiglath-Pileser III\'s (745 to 727 BCE) campaigns to the region, including the first known archeological reference to Judah (Yaudaya or KUR.ia-ú-da-a-a).'),
       ('Siloam inscription', '.png', 'c.701BCE', 'Siloam tunnel', 'Records the construction of Siloam tunnel'),
       ('Lachish relief', '.png', 'c.700BCE', 'Nineveh', 'Portion of the Sennacherib relief, which depicts captives from Judah being led into captivity after the Siege of Lachish in 701 BC.'),
       ('Azekah Inscription', '.png', 'c.700BCE', 'Library of Ashurbanipal', 'Describes an Assyrian campaign by Sennacherib against Hezekiah, King of Judah, including the conquest of Azekah.'),
       ('Sennacherib\'s Annals', '.png', 'c.690BCE' 'Nineveh, unprovenanced', 'Describes the Assyrian king Sennacherib\'s siege of Jerusalem in 701 BCE during the reign of king Hezekiah.'),
       ('Esarhaddon\'s Treaty with Ba\'al of Tyre', '.png', 'c.675BCE', 'Library of Ashurbanipal', 'Describes a treaty between Esarhaddon (reigned 681 to 669 BCE) and Ba\'al of Tyre with respect to pi-lis-te'),
       ('Ekron inscription', '.png', 'c.650BCE', 'Ekron', 'The first known inscription from the area ascribed to Philistines'),
       ('Cylinders of Nabonidus', '.png', 'c.550BCE', 'Ur', 'Describes Belshazzar (Balthazar) as Nabonidus\' eldest son'),
       ('Nabonidus Chronicle', '.png', '4th –1st century BCE', 'Sippar, unprovenanced', 'Describes the conquest of Babylon by the Persian king Cyrus the Great'),
       ('Cylinder of Cyrus', '.png', 'c.530BCE', 'Babylon', 'King Cyrus\'s treatment of religion, which is significant to the books of Chronicles, Ezra and Nehemiah.'),
       ('Temple Warning inscription', '.png', 'c.23 BCE – 70 CE', 'Jerusalem', 'Believed to be an inscription from Herod\'s Temple, warning foreigners ("allogenē") to refrain from entering the Temple enclosure'),
       ('Trumpeting Place inscription', '.png', 'c.1st century CE', 'Jerusalem', 'Believed to be a directional sign for the priests who blew a trumpet, consistent with an account in Josephus'),
       ('Arch of Titus', '.png', 'c.82CE', 'Roma', 'Relief showing spoils from the Sack of Jerusalem by Titus in 70 CE. Depicted are the menorah and trumpets, as well as what might be the Table of Showbread.');